Hello friends, today I will tell you that
if you have taken a loan from a bank and
they have forcibly given you a policy, then
how to cancel it.
See, what generally happens is that whether you
go for a home loan, personal loan or
business loan, the bank has forced you to take one or the other insurance
policy and it is forced
and they put a condition that they will
not disburse your loan if you do
not take this policy. See, there is a kind of pressure in this, see,
in many cases, not only the customers but the bank gets convinced, but what happens is that if there is so much compulsion, then
people have to take an insurance policy.
If you have been forced to take an insurance policy,
now how do you cancel it?
What happens in
insurance?
According to the norms of IRDA, there is a free
lookup period. The free lookup period is
generally between 15 to 30 days when
you receive the policy by post.
What happens after that in the free lookup,
IRDA, the insurance
regulatory body, says that if you
cancel your insurance policy under the free lookup, then  There will be
no penalty of any kind on you. So what
you have to do in free lookup is
that when the hard copy of the policy
reaches your home, at that very moment you have to
call the customer care of the insurance
company whose policy it is. You have to
call them from your registered mobile and
tell them that I do not want to take this policy,
you can cancel it immediately. If you want,
I can also record that call
so that if your
policy gets closed normally and what happens is that if
you get the free lookup done and cancel your policy within 15 days, then
you get all the money back
but if the free lookup period is over,
after that the policy is not cancelled. It is
simple, make a call and get it cancelled
and whatever amount you have, you will get a refund in the
bank account from which your money was deducted,
you will either get a cheque
or it will be RT or NFT.
Friends, we provide Pan India Personal Loan and
Business Loan. You can also earn commission up to 2% by
referring the file of any of your friends or relatives to us.  To
refer your file, you
can contact us on the number given above. Friends, if you
need a personal loan without insurance, that is,
without a policy, then you can contact us.
We will get your personal loan
done without an insurance policy and at the lowest
rate of interest in the market. Thank you.